Art meets science.
Chasing Ice is a documentary film directed by Jeff Orlowski.
When National Geographic photographer James Balog asked, “How can one take a
picture of climate change?” his attention was immediately drawn to ice.
Soon he was asked to do a cover story on glaciers that became the most popular
and well-read piece in the magazine during the last five years.
But for Balog, that story marked the beginning of a much larger and
longer-term project that would reach epic proportions.
Self - Photographer, played by James Balog.
Self - Photo Assistant, played by Svavar Jonatansson.
Self - EIS Engineer, played by Adam LeWinter.
Self - Photographer & Oscar Winning Filmmaker, played by Louie Psihoyos.
Self - The Aspen Institute, played by Kitty Boone.
Self - National Geographic Explorer, played by Sylvia Earle.
Chasing Ice is a 2012 documentary film about the efforts of nature photographer James Balog
and his Extreme Ice Survey (EIS) to publicize the effects of climate change.
The film was directed by Jeff Orlowski.
It was released in the United States on November 16, 2012.
The documentary includes scenes from a glacier calving event that took place at Jacobshavn Isbræ
in Greenland, lasting 75 minutes, the longest such event ever captured on film.
Two EIS videographers waited several weeks in a small tent overlooking the glacier and,
finally, witnessed 7.4 cubic kilometres (1.8 cu mi) of ice crashing off the glacier.
"The calving of a massive glacier believed to have produced the ice that
sank the Titanic is like watching a city break apart."
The film explores themes of climate change, global
warming, glacier, environment, field research.